A Guide to the Dan H. Pletta Papers, 1958-1994
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
- Box 7, 1972-1983, n.d.
  - National Academy of Engineering - Boley Report. (Box-folder 7-258)
  - Engineers Council for Professional Development (ECPD). (Box-folder 7-259)
  - Engineering Organization- American Society of Engineering Education Visiting Engineers Program. (Box-folder 7-260)
  - Engineering Organization - American Bar Association (ABA)/American Medical Association (AMA). (Box-folder 7-261)
  - Engineering Organization - NSF Workshop - Ethics, 1979. (Box-folder 7-262)
  - Miscellaneous - Yeshiva University Unionization, 1979-1980. (Box-folder 7-263)
  - General Correspondence - Engineers' Council for Professional Development (ECPD). (Box-folder 7-264)
  - Engineers' Council for Professional Development (ECPD)/ABET Workshop, 1972. (Box-folder 7-265)
  - Education Council - Lafayette Correspondence, 1962-1974. (Box-folder 7-266)
  - Long Range Strategy Memo. (Box-folder 7-267)
  - National Society Professional Engineers (NSPE)/ Public Advocacy Review Board (PARB) Special Task Force, 1983. (Box-folder 7-268)
  - NSPE/ PARB - Survey Questionnaire to Charters, Fall 1983. (Box-folder 7-269)
  - NSPE/ PARB - Correspondence, December 31, 1984. (Box-folder 7-270)
  - Order of the Engineers- National Correspondence. (Box-folder 7-271)
  - Order of the Engineers- National Correspondence, December 31, 1984. (Box-folder 7-272)
  - TORCH - "Are Foxes Guarding the New House?" (Box-folder 7-273)
  - Society for Experimental Stress Analysis (SESA) - "Lest We Forget" / Stanford Mechanics Alumni Club (SMAC) Newsletter "That Extra Effort." (Box-folder 7-274)
  - Materials and Society, "Engineering Unity: 20/20 Hindsight in year 2020." (Box-folder 7-275)
  - "Engineering's Emerging Public Purpose." (Box-folder 7-276)
  - American Society for Engineering Management (ASEM) - NSPE Paper. (Box-folder 7-277)
  - Professional Schools Miscellaneous - Faculty Union. (Box-folder 7-278)
  - Miscellaneous -UDAPI/EJC Mexico- H. F. Brinson. (Box-folder 7-279)
  - Engineering Organization - American Concrete Institute committee. (Box-folder 7-280)
  - International Association for Housing Science. (Box-folder 7-281)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, January 1, 1982 - December 31, 1984. (Box-folder 7-282)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1982-1983. (Box-folder 7-283)
- Box 8, 1982-1991, n.d.
  - US Congress and State Legislators. (Box-folder 8-284)
  - Letters - Editor. (Box-folder 8-285)
  - Cornell University - Lyon White. (Box-folder 8-286)
  - VPI Administration - Miscellaneous. (Box-folder 8-287)
  - Lobbying Highway Trucks. (Box-folder 8-288)
  - Miscellaneous - Stops- World Tour, April 1982. (Box-folder 8-289)
  - News Record Citation. (Box-folder 8-290)
  - Miscellaneous - Arizona State University. (Box-folder 8-291)
  - Permanent Magnet Foundation Charitable Trust/Howard Johnson. (Box-folder 8-292)
  - Louis Guy. (Box-folder 8-293)
  - Harris Wesley - MIT & Leon Trilling. (Box-folder 8-294)
  - Alfred Ingersol. (Box-folder 8-295)
  - Itani, Rafik. (Box-folder 8-296)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1984-1986. (Box-folder 8-297)
  - Buglidrello, George - NY Polytechnic Institute. (Box-folder 8-298)
  - "St. Patrick was an engineer, he was.. ."/ Music. (Box-folder 8-299)
  - Miscellaneous Talks. (Box-folder 8-300)
  - VPI Admin./Dean of Engineering/Report of TX A&M Mtg., August 25-27, 1991. (Box-folder 8-301)
  - Miscellaneous Lobbying - Highway Trucks. (Box-folder 8-302)
  - UDP - Center for Civilian Leadership Consulting Liability Coverage. (Box-folder 8-303)
  - VPI Educational Foundation Support. (Box-folder 8-304)
  - VPI Faculty Ethics Committee. (Box-folder 8-305)
  - VPI Administration (1). (Box-folder 8-306)
  - VPI Administration (2). (Box-folder 8-307)
  - U.S. Congress - VA Legislature (1). (Box-folder 8-308)
  - U.S. Congress - VA Legislature (2). (Box-folder 8-309)
  - Unions - Academic. (Box-folder 8-310)
  - Hardy Cross - J. A. Rives. (Box-folder 8-311)
  - Center for Civilian Leadership. (Box-folder 8-312)
  - Letters to the Editor (1). (Box-folder 8-313)
  - Letters to the Editor (2). (Box-folder 8-314)
  - Letters to the Editor (3). (Box-folder 8-315)
  - Cornell University. (Box-folder 8-316)
  - Sikarskie, David L. (Box-folder 8-317)
  - Correspondence, 1996. (Box-folder 8-318)
  - Correspondence, 1995. (Box-folder 8-319)
  - Correspondence (1), 1993-1994. (Box-folder 8-320)
  - Correspondence (2), 1993-1994. (Box-folder 8-321)
  - Correspondence, 1992. (Box-folder 8-322)
  - Correspondence, 1991. (Box-folder 8-323)
  - Correspondence, 1990. (Box-folder 8-324)
  - Correspondence, 1989. (Box-folder 8-325)
  - Correspondence, 1988. (Box-folder 8-326)
  - Correspondence, 1987. (Box-folder 8-327)
  - Cairns, John. (Box-folder 8-328)
  - Comparin, Robert, Dean, California State University. (Box-folder 8-329)
  - NSPE - Cox, William A. (Box-folder 8-330)
  - Davis, R.T., Symposium. (Box-folder 8-331)
  - Dorats, Peter, University New Mexico. (Box-folder 8-332)
  - Louis Guy. (Box-folder 8-333)
  - Crasty - Whistle Blowing - Ethics. (Box-folder 8-334)
  - Wenk, Edward Jr. (2). (Box-folder 8-335)
  - Wenk, Edward Jr. (1). (Box-folder 8-336)
- Box 9, 1954-1994, n.d.
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1984-1986. (Box-folder 9-337)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1984-1986. (Box-folder 9-338)
  - Ackerman, Adolph J. (Box-folder 9-339)
  - Johnson, Howard. (Box-folder 9-340)
  - William F. Jones. (Box-folder 9-341)
  - Leslie D. Myers. (Box-folder 9-342)
  - Gracie Reynolds - Woman of the Year. (Box-folder 9-343)
  - C.W. Smith. (Box-folder 9-344)
  - E.Q. Smith. (Box-folder 9-345)
  - Joseph Lestingi - Manhattan College. (Box-folder 9-346)
  - Dr. Liu Ruiting - China. (Box-folder 9-347)
  - Lunch, Milton F./NSPE. (Box-folder 9-348)
  - Book Review - David Reyes-Guerra; Correspondence. (Box-folder 9-349)
  - Krammerer, Allan M./ASCE Mock Hearing. (Box-folder 9-350)
  - Dundar Kocaogiu - University of Pittsburgh. (Box-folder 9-351)
  - Joseph S. Ward (1). (Box-folder 9-352)
  - Joseph S. Ward (2). (Box-folder 9-353)
  - J. Ron Winter. (Box-folder 9-354)
  - Nayfen, Ali Yarmouk - University of Jordan. (Box-folder 9-355)
  - Rabinow, Jacob. (Box-folder 9-356)
  - National Academy of Engineering - Anton Tedesko. (Box-folder 9-357)
  - Letters to the Editor. (Box-folder 9-358)
  - N.Y. State License - University of Illinois Transcripts. (Box-folder 9-359)
  - Engineering News Record Citation, February 19, 1972. (Box-folder 9-360)
  - Pletta - Miscellaneous Career Correspondence. (Box-folder 9-361)
  - News Items - Pletta. (Box-folder 9-362)
  - Vienna. (Box-folder 9-363)
  - University Distinguished Professor (1), 1970. (Box-folder 9-364)
  - University Distinguished Professor (2), 1970. (Box-folder 9-365)
  - University of Illinois Award, April 23, 1976. (Box-folder 9-366)
  - Engineering. Statics & Dynanics. 1951, Engineering Mechanics 1964, Ronald Press/John Wiley. (Box-folder 9-367)
  - NSPE - Professional Tour & Professional Unity - Samson /NSPE Meeting, January 1988. (Box-folder 9-368)
  - NSPE Correspondence. (Box-folder 9-369)
  - VSPE - SW Chapter - Constitution & Bylaws Committee. (Box-folder 9-370)
  - VSPE /Virginia Section Resolution - Overrule Judgement. (Box-folder 9-371)
  - Virginia - Licensing Law/Exemptions - FL & VA, 1967-1977. (Box-folder 9-372)
  - VSPE Legislature Committee. (Box-folder 9-373)
  - VSPE Task Force on Overruling Engineers. (Box-folder 9-374)
  - VSPE Engineering Information Committee/Ethics & Practices Committee. (Box-folder 9-375)
  - VSPE Installation of Officers. (Box-folder 9-376)
  - VSPE Correspondence, 1981 to date. (Box-folder 9-377)
  - VSPE Meeting, 1992-1993. (Box-folder 9-378)
  - VSPE Past President's Luncheon, June 19, 1993. (Box-folder 9-379)
  - VSPE Past President's Council, 1988-1991. (Box-folder 9-380)
  - VSPE Case 90-1: James V. Powell, 1st Report. (Box-folder 9-381)
  - VSPE Professional School Task Force (Box-folder 9-382)
  - VSPE Ethics & Practices Committee. (Box-folder 9-383)
  - VSPE Correspondence, 1994. (Box-folder 9-384)
  - VSPE 1990 Correspondence/Insurance. (Box-folder 9-385)
  - VSPE - Ethics & Practices Committee, Case 90-1/ad hoc Inquiry - Virginia Beach. (Box-folder 9-386)
  - VSPE Milton Costello Materials. (Box-folder 9-387)
  - Pletta Award. (Box-folder 9-388)
  - VSPE 1990 Memos & Minutes, Reports. (Box-folder 9-389)
  - Introduction to Engineering. (Box-folder 9-390)
  - Dan H. Pletta Professorship, 1992. (Box-folder 9-391)
  - Pletta - Resumes, Who's Who Photos, etc. (Box-folder 9-392)
  - Awards. (Box-folder 9-393)
  - Pletta Scholarship University Distinguished Professor, VPI & SU Outstanding Senior Project. (Box-folder 9-394)
  - Pletta Ruffner Award. (Box-folder 9-395)
  - The Three Faces of Dan Pletta. (Box-folder 9-396)
  - Illinois Institute of Technology Conference - Ethics in Engineering, March 1982. (Box-folder 9-397)
  - NSPE Programs - 2000 Task Force. (Box-folder 9-398)
  - NSPE Publications Committee Correspondence. (Box-folder 9-399)
  - NSPE - Publications Committee Reports. (Box-folder 9-400)
  - NSPE - Public Advocacy Review Board Survey Questionnaire. (Box-folder 9-401)
  - Registration and Qualifications for Practice Committee Report, 1980. (Box-folder 9-402)
- Box 10, 1976-1995, n.d.
  - Public Advocacy Review Board (PARB) - 1984, John F. Heneage (1). (Box-folder 10-403)
  - PARB - 1984, John F. Heneage (2). (Box-folder 10-404)
  - PARB - Letters to the Editor, Reports, Correspondence, 1985. (Box-folder 10-405)
  - NSPE - PARB Correspondence, 1985-1986. (Box-folder 10-406)
  - NSPE - PAR Board Correspondence, 1982-1985. (Box-folder 10-407)
  - Public Advocacy Review Board. (Box-folder 10-408)
  - ASCE, Research Council on Performance of Structures, 1983-1984. (Box-folder 10-409)
  - ASCE - Consent Degree Violation. (Box-folder 10-410)
  - ASCE Correspondence - Virginia Section (1). (Box-folder 10-411)
  - ASCE Correspondence - Virginia Section (2). (Box-folder 10-412)
  - ASCE Correspondence - Virginia Section (3). (Box-folder 10-413)
  - ASCE - Key Alert. (Box-folder 10-414)
  - ASCE Policy Statements, May 1986. (Box-folder 10-415)
  - ASCE Policy Statements. (Box-folder 10-416)
  - ASCE Speaker's Kit. (Box-folder 10-417)
  - ASCE Speaker's Kit. (Box-folder 10-418)
  - ASCE Misc. Student Chapters. (Box-folder 10-419)
  - Order of the Engineer, 1995. (Box-folder 10-420)
  - Order of the Engineer meeting, 1989-1992. (Box-folder 10-421)
  - Order of the Engineer meeting, 1990. (Box-folder 10-422)
  - Order of the Engineer, Inc., Annual Report, 1980-1981. (Box-folder 10-423)
  - Order of the Engineer, April 1-2, 1989. (Box-folder 10-424)
  - Order of the Engineer, National Correspondence, July 1980 to September 1987. (Box-folder 10-425)
  - Order of the Engineer, National Correspondence, July 1980 to September 1987. (Box-folder 10-426)
  - Order of the Engineer Meeting, 1994. (Box-folder 10-427)
  - To Be an Engineer. (Box-folder 10-428)
  - NSPE Annual Meeting, 1979. (Box-folder 10-429)
  - To Be an Engineer. (Box-folder 10-430)
  - Order of the Engineer - Stationery Virginia Link - Correspondence. (Box-folder 10-431)
  - Order of the Engineer, VPI Link, Correspondence. (Box-folder 10-432)
  - Order of the Engineer./National Board Correspondence to December 1976 (Box-folder 10-433)
  - Conference, Ethics Professional & Maintaining Competence, Ohio State University. (Box-folder 10-434)
  - ASCE - CPC "Ethics on Trial," Video Tape. (Box-folder 10-435)
  - Comments Cosoro Input. (Box-folder 10-436)
  - ASCE - CPC/Professional Conduct Case Studies. (Box-folder 10-437)
  - ASCE Misc./ECPD Accreditation Handbook. (Box-folder 10-438)
  - ASCE South America Tour, 1976. (Box-folder 10-439)
  - ASCE Asian Tour, 1978. (Box-folder 10-440)
  - ASCE South Pacific and Australian Tours, 1981. (Box-folder 10-441)
  - Order of the Engineering Meeting, March 23-24, 1991. (Box-folder 10-442)
  - Order of the Engineering meeting, October 31, 1992. (Box-folder 10-443)
  - ASEE-Australia, 1981. (Box-folder 10-444)
  - ABET Advanced Accreditation. (Box-folder 10-445)
  - ASCE - Committee on Public Affairs & Legislation. (Box-folder 10-446)
  - Carter, Archie. (Box-folder 10-447)
- Box 11
  - Committee on Engineering Management & Leadership. (Box-folder 11-448)
  - Committee on Engineering Management & Leadership. (Box-folder 11-449)
  - Order of the Engineering Meeting, November 5-7, 1992. (Box-folder 11-450)
  - To Be an Engineer - Pamphlet. (Box-folder 11-451)
  - Order of the Engineer National Correspondence, January 1977 - July 1990. (Box-folder 11-452)
  - Sigma XI at Virginia Polytechnic Institute. (Box-folder 11-453)
  - Guiding Technology. (Box-folder 11-454)
  - McGraw-Hill Review - Steven Ross, 1981. (Box-folder 11-455)
  - Miscellaneous Book Reviews. (Box-folder 11-456)
  - ASCE Articles-Are We Educating Engineering Professionals? (Box-folder 11-457)
  - Discussion, paper by Kenneth A. Roe. (Box-folder 11-458)
  - ASCE Article, "Ethical Codes-Enforcement vs. Obedience." (Box-folder 11-459)
  - Miscellaneous Articles/IIT Lecture Correspondence. (Box-folder 11-460)
  - "Engineering Professionalism-Light at the End of the Tunnel." (Box-folder 11-461)
  - "Trends in Faculty Qualifications and Objectives," 1974. (Box-folder 11-462)
  - ASCE Article, "The Making of a Pro," 1974. (Box-folder 11-463)
  - ASCE Article, "Ingeniur Diplomats - Public Advocates Worldwide," 1976. (Box-folder 11-464)
  - ASCE Article, "Engineering Leadership and Technological Teamwork." (Box-folder 11-465)
  - "What If." (Box-folder 11-466)
  - "Engineering: Answers for the 1980s"/"Beyond Whistle Blowing." (Box-folder 11-467)
  - NSPE Engineering Times, Letter to the Editor, June 20, 1991. (Box-folder 11-468)
  - "The Development of Professional Schools." (Box-folder 11-469)
  - Professional Conflicts, Faculty Unions. (Box-folder 11-470)
  - ASEE, 1987 Meeting, Reno: "Excellence in Engineering. Education." (Box-folder 11-471)
  - ASEE Articles. (Box-folder 11-472)
  - Discussion of Victor Paschkis Paper. (Box-folder 11-473)
  - "Personally Speaking - Professional Freedom for Responsible Practice," 1978. (Box-folder 11-474)
  - "Coupling Economics with Ethics for Employed Engineers," 1977. (Box-folder 11-475)
  - "Collective Bargaining and Engineering. Faculties." (Box-folder 11-476)
  - "Consulting and Licensing of Engineering Faculties." (Box-folder 11-477)
  - Engineering Education Crisis - ASEE, Professional Engineering Programs. (Box-folder 11-478)
  - "A Proposed Concept for a Practice Oriented Professional Degree in Engineering." (Box-folder 11-479)
  - "Source Funding and Destination of Grad Student in Mech," 1970. (Box-folder 11-480)
  - Discussion: "Fundamentals of Engineering Examination Review." (Box-folder 11-481)
  - Discussion "Engagement of Engineers in Science Policy." (Box-folder 11-482)
  - "Civil Engineering Design Professionals Should Be Regular Engineers." (Box-folder 11-483)
  - "Whistleblowing." (Box-folder 11-484)
  - "The Overstressed Transportation Issue," Robert Schumacher and Pletta. (Box-folder 11-485)
  - Discussion: "Dialogue on Political Contributions and Engineering." (Box-folder 11-486)
  - Professional Support for Safety: Conscious Whistleblowers. (Box-folder 11-487)
  - Discussion: Visioning. (Box-folder 11-488)
  - Discussion: "Why Four Years?" (Box-folder 11-489)
  - "Engineering Responsibility," April 1987. (Box-folder 11-490)
  - "Is an Expanded Role for Engineers. Needed?" (Box-folder 11-491)
  - "Public Affairs Activity: Seeds of Reality." (Box-folder 11-492)
  - Discussion: "Developing Countries: High Tech or Innovative Management," 1989. (Box-folder 11-493)
  - Discussion: "Life Cycle Engineering." (Box-folder 11-494)
  - "To Practice or Perish," Pletta and George A. Gray. (Box-folder 11-495)
  - "Uninvolved Professionals and Technical Disasters." (Box-folder 11-496)
  - "Social Science Emphasis in Engineering Education." (Box-folder 11-497)
  - "Tomorrow's Professional Engineer--Public's Advocate?" (Box-folder 11-498)
  - "Why Professional Schools for Engineers?" (Box-folder 11-499)
  - "Engineering Leadership and Crisis Control," 1978. (Box-folder 11-500)
  - "Society's Needs: Leaders"; "The Status of Collective Bargaining in Engineering," (Box-folder 11-501)
  - "The Engineer - His Brother's Keeper," 1971. (Box-folder 11-502)
  - "Unionized Faculties" (1973), "When Is Engineering Registration Required?" (1965), "Quo Vadimus" (1952). (Box-folder 11-503)
  - "Professionalism: An Added Dimension," 1980. (Box-folder 11-504)
  - TORCH Awards Committee and Correspondence. (Box-folder 11-505)
  - "Needed: An Engineering Manifesto for a Higher Calling." (Box-folder 11-506)
  - Montgomery County Torch Club. (Box-folder 11-507)
  - "The Biggest Game in Town." (Box-folder 11-508)
  - "Are Foxes Guarding the Hen House?" (Box-folder 11-509)
  - SESA & Stanford Mechanics Alumni News Letter. (Box-folder 11-510)
  - "The Engineering Professions Dual Challenge," VPI & SU (Box-folder 11-511)
  - "The Engineer's Destiny." (Box-folder 11-512)
  - "Engineering's Emerging Public Purpose." (Box-folder 11-513)
  - Virginia Academy of Science (1985); "The Technologist's Political Impotence." (Box-folder 11-514)
  - "Grooming the Engineer's Personality for his Profession's Emerging Public Purpose." (Box-folder 11-515)
  - Engineering Unity: 20/20 Hindsight. (Box-folder 11-516)
  - Economic and Political Constraints. (Box-folder 11-517)
  - Education. (Box-folder 11-518)
  - Ethics. (Box-folder 11-519)
  - Miscellaneous; Association of Professional Engineers of Ontario; Stephen Jack. (Box-folder 11-520)
  - Whistleblowing Correspondence. (Box-folder 11-521)
  - Miscellaneous Papers: "Fatigue Life Reduction," "All Nailed Lumber Truss." (Box-folder 11-522)
  - Miscellaneous Papers: Wood Flooring Systems. (Box-folder 11-523)
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Reports. (Box-folder 11-524)
- Box 12
  - Script for Engineering Fund. Video Tape on Professionalism and Ethics. (Box-folder 12-525)
  - Miscellaneous Talks, University of Kansas. (Box-folder 12-526)
  - ABET National Congress on Engineering Education, 1986. (Box-folder 12-527)
  - Needed: An Engineering Manifesto and a Patron Saint." (Box-folder 12-528)
  - Professional Schools - VPI Professional School Task Force. (Box-folder 12-529)
  - Professional Schools - VPI Reports, May 1974. (Box-folder 12-530)
  - Professional Schools ABET 1986 Congress: Pritzker, Eldon. Cranch, Nordby. (Box-folder 12-531)
  - Professional Schools - Charles W. Matheny Correspondence. (Box-folder 12-532)
  - Texas Higher Education Coordinating Board, Educational Consulting, 1995. (Box-folder 12-533)
  - Professional Schools - Arizona State University Report, 1992. (Box-folder 12-534)
  - Professional Schools - NSPE/PEE, Criteria, Long-Range Strategy Memo, 1977. (Box-folder 12-535)
  - VPI/BET Phase Out. (Box-folder 12-536)
  - ASME Symposium on Technological Change, 1989. (Box-folder 12-537)
  - University of London - External Degrees. (Box-folder 12-538)
  - International Participatory Engineering Society (Pletta and Halbert Brinson), 1980. (Box-folder 12-539)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box-folder 12-540)
  - Engineering Organization, American Academy of Mechanics. (Box-folder 12-541)
  - The Engineering Profession and Its Public Purpose. (Box-folder 12-542)
  - Engineering Organization American Society of Engineering Management. (Box-folder 12-543)
  - Engineering Organization: ABA and AMA Professional Standards and Engineering. (Box-folder 12-544)
  - Engineers Joint Council-AAES-ABET. (Box-folder 12-545)
  - National Science Foundation Workshop - Ethics - World Future Society. (Box-folder 12-546)
  - Unity - Engineers Joint Council - AAES. (Box-folder 12-547)
  - Omicron Delta Kappa. (Box-folder 12-548)
  - Virginia Tech College of Engineering. (Box-folder 12-549)
  - Quotes. (Box-folder 12-550)
  - Patent Policy. (Box-folder 12-551)
  - Miscellaneous Articles on Professional Engineers. (Box-folder 12-552)
  - Admiral H. G. Rickover, "A Humanistic Technology." (Box-folder 12-553)
  - "The Energy Age," David A. Mathison. (Box-folder 12-554)
  - Maestros of Tech - Arthur M. Squires. (Box-folder 12-555)
  - "The Importance of the Bicentennial for Engineers." (Box-folder 12-556)
  - Robert L. Whitelaw. (Box-folder 12-557)
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Reports (1). (Box-folder 12-558)
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Reports (2). (Box-folder 12-559)
  - Howard R. Johnson Brakes and Magnetic Motors. (Box-folder 12-560)
  - Summary--Engineers in the Literature. (Box-folder 12-561)
  - Ingenior. (Box-folder 12-562)
  - Educational Consulting. (Box-folder 12-563)
  - Texas A&M, February 16, 1988. (Box-folder 12-564)
  - Lindbergh Fund Proposal, 1985. (Box-folder 12-565)
  - Trucks -- Francis Sherry. (Box-folder 12-566)
  - Educational Consulting/Dr. S.J. Brown/Akron, Ohio. (Box-folder 12-567)
  - Governor's Magnet School/Radford University, 1985. (Box-folder 12-568)
  - MSPE Student Chapter, March 20, 1986. (Box-folder 12-569)
  - An Engineering Manifesto. (Box-folder 12-570)
  - Paul Craft, Jr./Radial Engine. (Box-folder 12-571)
  - Virginia Tech Curriculum and Departments; Miscellaneous Articles. (Box-folder 12-572)
  - Correspondence, Miscellaneous. (Box-folder 12-573)
  - Engineering's Unity and Expanding Obligation/NSPE Engineering Times and Letters to the Editor. (Box-folder 12-574)
  - South Africa Trip, 1980. (Box-folder 12-575)
  - United States and China People's Friendship Association. (Box-folder 12-576)
  - Nickolai Mahutou (USSR); International Congress. (Box-folder 12-577)
  - H. Kenneth Rigsbee: Restructuring Engineering Education: Virginia Tech College of Engineering Report: Professional Engineering Program (Box-folder 12-578)
  - International Alliance of Ingeniors Constitution; Letters to ABET. (Box-folder 12-579)
  - Memories of the first 40 years: History of Engineering Mechanics at Virginia Tech. (Box-folder 12-580)
  - Virginia Tech Presidential Symposium, University Distinguished Professors. (Box-folder 12-581)
  - Institute of Global Ethics. (Box-folder 12-582)
  - Nature of Engineering course; Correspondence; Miscellaneous. (Box-folder 12-583)
- Box 13
  - Mechanics and Notes. (Box-folder 13-584)
  - Articles & Reports on Education, Ethics, and Professionalism. (Box-folder 13-585)
  - Beam Notes. (Box-folder 13-586)
  - Direct Magazine/Consulting. (Box-folder 13-587)
  - Dresser Ideco Company/Guyed Towers. (Box-folder 13-588)
  - Ferguson - Cinder Blocks. (Box-folder 13-589)
  - Consulting/Joan Gibson, Moustafa Gadalla. (Box-folder 13-590)
  - Extras. (Box-folder 13-591)
  - Harper Engine. (Box-folder 13-592)
  - Tapps Store Building - Columbia, SC. (Box-folder 13-593)
  - Naval Missile Center - Centrifuge Report. (Box-folder 13-594)
  - Liberty Mutual Insurance. (Box-folder 13-595)
  - Reynolds Metals - Bumper; notable letterhead from Richmond Engineering Company. (Box-folder 13-596)
  - Beam Failure. (Box-folder 13-597)
  - Naval Missile Center - Centrifuge - Point Mugu, California (1). (Box-folder 13-598)
  - Naval Missile Center - Centrifuge - Point Mugu, California (2). (Box-folder 13-599)
  - Point Mugu Correspondence. (Box-folder 13-599A)
  - Smelting Company, - Norfolk, Virginia/Concrete Tanks. (Box-folder 13-600)
  - Bar Joists/Long Span/Open Web Joists (Virginia Steel Company). (Box-folder 13-601)
  - Figures - Chapters 1,2,7. (Box-folder 13-602)
  - Owen's Building - Wind Analysis. (Box-folder 13-603)
  - Ultimate Flexural Strength of Reinforced Concrete/Plasticity. (Box-folder 13-604)
  - Moment Distribution/U.S.M.A. Notes. (Box-folder 13-605)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. (Box-folder 13-606)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. (Box-folder 13-607)
  - Proceedings of the Workshop on Developing Guidelines for Recognition of Professional Schools of Engineering. (Box-folder 13-608)